Finding Aid for Muehlig Funeral Chapel records, 1846-1867 and 1882-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Muehlig Funeral Chapel records 1846-1867 and 1882-1995 1846-1867 and 1882-1916
Muehlig Funeral Chapel
2 linear ft.
047 Bb 2
Firm established in Ann Arbor, Michigan in the mid-nineteenth century as a furniture-undertaking business. Ledgers and daybooks of furniture and undertaking business, 1846-1867; funeral record books, 1882-1916, containing such vital information as name, date of death, age, cause of death, and occupation; register, 1919-1940, of funerals, containing names only. The records from May 1909 through 1916 include occasional information about deceased's parents.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were donated by Muehlig Funeral Chapel (donor no. 9400 ) in December 2003
The record group is open to research.
The series in this record group include: Funeral Records; Funeral Record Books; Miscellaneous Funeral Records; and Financial Records.
Subjects:
Muehlig Funeral Chapel.; Ann Arbor (Mich.); German Americans--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Undertakers and undertaking--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
- Funeral Records (early miscellaneous)
  - 1882-1889 (Box 1)
    (includes name, date of death, age and cause of death)
  - 1896-1900 (Box 1)
    (includes name, date of death, age and cause of death; also itemization of funeral expenses)
- Funeral Record Books
  (includes vital information, age, cause of death, occupation; records following May 1909 also includes information about parents)
  - January 1898-June 1902 (Box 1)
  - June 1902-December 1904 (Box 1)
  - December 1904-July 1906 (Box 1)
  - July 1906-February 1908 (Box 1)
  - February 1908-May 1909 (Box 1)
  - May 1909-August 1912 (Box 1)
  - August 1912-December 1916 (Box 1)
  - 1919-1940 (Box 1)
    (list of names only, arranged by month of burial date)
- Miscellaneous funeral records
  - Inventory book, ca. 1920 (Box 1)
    (cover of volume reads "Ambulance")
  - Inventory book, 1952-1995 (Box 1)
- Financial Records
  (furniture and undertaking business; these volumes, written in German, do not include vital information)
  - Ledgers (with index), 1846-1867, 3 volumes and 1 folder (Box 2)
  - Daybooks, 1849-1866, 3 volumes (Box 2)